<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-30T12:12:55+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tevy Tunsay</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your site.</subtitle><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><entry><title type="html">Breaking the Cage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/breakingthecage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking the Cage" /><published>2024-11-26T15:04:00+11:00</published><updated>2024-11-26T15:04:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/breakingthecage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/breakingthecage/"><![CDATA[<p>In a quiet town, beneath elm trees shaped by age and tradition, lived a woman with a secret pressed deep inside her chest. She had been taught that love was duty; marriage was legacy. She followed the path expected of her, marrying a kind man whose devotion was constant.
He was gentle; his love was steady and patient. He built a home around her comfort, never doubting her smiles. She cared for him deeply, but not in the way he deserved. Her love was affection, not passion; friendship, not desire. Her heart longed for something she could not speak.</p>

<p>When their child was born, her world seemed complete in the eyes of others. She cherished her little one, held them close, sang them to sleep. Yet even in moments of joy, guilt gnawed at her. She felt like a fraud; she could give her child tenderness, but not the kind of honest family born from truth. The cage of her silence grew tighter, its bars pressing into her soul.</p>

<p>Years passed, and the secret within her only grew heavier. She loved—but not her husband. Her heart had always belonged to women, though she had buried that truth under duty. Then, one autumn evening, as the trees burned gold and crimson, she met someone who woke the self she had silenced.</p>

<p>She was vibrant and alive. In her gaze, the woman rediscovered a part of herself long buried. Their quiet talks grew into love, and for the first time she felt free. Yet with every moment of joy came the sharp guilt—toward the man who had given her kindness, and toward the child who needed her.</p>

<p>One night, unable to live in the shadows any longer, she confessed. Her voice trembled as she spoke of the truth; that her heart belonged to a woman, not to him. She braced herself for fury. Instead, she met only sorrow.</p>

<p>“I want you to be happy,” he whispered, his voice breaking. “Even if that happiness is not with me.”</p>

<p>His forgiveness crushed her more than anger ever could. She looked at her child, asleep in another room, and felt her heart fracture. She was a mother who loved deeply; yet she was also a woman who needed to be free.</p>

<p>They parted with tenderness and tears. He kept their child close, steady as always. She stepped into an uncertain future, filled with fear and longing, her heart torn between love for her child and the need to live her truth.</p>

<p>The road ahead was uncharted; yet with each step she followed the rhythm of her heart, no longer silenced. She would always carry guilt, but she chose honesty over a lifetime of shadows.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shame She Cannot Bury</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/shame-she-cannot-bury/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shame She Cannot Bury" /><published>2024-10-26T15:04:00+11:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T15:04:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/shame-she-cannot-bury</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/shame-she-cannot-bury/"><![CDATA[<p>She was once the kind of girl everyone admired. Graceful, disciplined, and full of promise, she carried herself with quiet confidence. Every step she took was measured, every word she spoke was thoughtful. Parents spoke her name with pride, teachers pointed to her as an example, and friends respected her composure. She seemed untouchable, a symbol of honour and hope in a world that often demanded less.</p>

<p>Her youth was bright with possibilities. She dreamed of a life built on integrity, of achievements earned with effort and discipline. The girl she was believed in right and wrong with certainty. She believed her future would always follow the straight path she had chosen, because she trusted herself to never wander.</p>

<p>Then she met him. His presence shook her carefully built world. He was unlike anything she had known, a storm to her calm, fire to her water. With him, the rules no longer seemed so firm. Her heart raced in ways she had never felt before. For the first time, she understood what it meant to lose control, and that loss both thrilled and frightened her.</p>

<p>At first she tried to resist, but love has a way of bending reason. Slowly, almost without noticing, she began to step away from the girl she had always been. Boundaries that once seemed unbreakable blurred into something softer. She made choices she once thought she never could. Each time, she told herself it was only once, only a mistake. Yet with every moment, she drifted further from the version of herself she had been so proud of.</p>

<p>It was not only her actions that changed, but the way she saw herself. The girl of honour was gone, replaced by someone she hardly recognised. She knew it, and yet she could not stop. Love had become a force greater than discipline, and desire had silenced the voice of conscience. What she did in those days became memories she would never be able to erase, memories that clung to her like shadows.</p>

<p>Years passed, but time did not wash them away. If anything, time sharpened them. As she grew older, she felt the gaze of her younger self more and more. She remembered that girl clearly, the one who had been pure, determined, and full of dignity. That girl would have looked at the woman she became with sorrow, perhaps even disgust. It was this silent judgement that cut the deepest, the knowledge that she had betrayed herself.</p>

<p>She carried her shame in silence. Outwardly, she lived her life, but inside she was marked by regret. No one around her knew the weight she carried, yet she felt it in every step. She often wondered what her life might have been if she had chosen differently, if she had held to her principles. She thought of the reputation she had lost, of the respect she had once inspired, and her heart ached with the knowledge that it could never be recovered.</p>

<p>There were moments when she tried to forgive herself, to believe that mistakes were part of life, that everyone stumbles. She reflected that youth is rarely as clear as it seems, that the ideals of a young heart often meet the storms of reality. Yet even as she tried to find peace, the ache of regret remained. It was not simply that she had made mistakes, but that she had abandoned the very values she had once cherished.</p>

<p>Now, as a woman, she walks with a dignity that is different from before. It is no longer the flawless, untouchable grace of youth. It is the fragile dignity of someone who has lived, fallen, and struggled to rise again. She has learned, she has endured, and she has survived. Yet deep inside, the regret remains, heavy and unyielding.</p>

<p>She knows she cannot change the past. She cannot go back to the girl she once was, nor erase the choices that shaped her. The shame is part of her, carved into her spirit. Still, she carries on, because life demands it. She carries both her triumphs and her mistakes, even though the weight of regret will never fully lift.</p>

<p>Her story is not one of perfection, but of humanity. It is the story of a girl who fell from grace, of a woman who learned the hard truth that some mistakes cannot be undone. She lives with that truth, day after day, knowing that time cannot heal everything. What remains is the strength to keep walking, even when the past follows like a shadow.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">23 April 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/23April2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="23 April 2018" /><published>2024-09-26T14:04:00+10:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T14:04:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/23April2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/23April2018/"><![CDATA[<p>It was a little after 5 a.m. when a terrified scream startled me awake. I thought it was another one of my sister’s usual panicked reactions to a centipede or some other harmless creature.</p>

<p>But something about this scream felt different; deeper, more desperate.</p>

<p>I rushed out of my room, my heart pounding. My bedroom is right by the stairs, and as I stepped into the hallway, time seemed to freeze. There she was; my sister; crying, her face pale, eyes wide with terror, staring up the staircase.
I followed her gaze and felt my heart stop. My grandmother was hanging from the top of the stairs.</p>

<p>Everything after that moved in a blur. My father rushed forward, hands trembling as he frantically tried to untie the rope. We pulled her down, laying her fragile body on the floor. Without a second thought, we began CPR, desperately hoping to revive her, though we had no idea how long she had been up there. Every breath felt like an eternity, the eerie sound of air escaping her lungs echoing in the room. We clung to the tiny hope that it was a sign she might still be alive.</p>

<p>But deep down, we knew.</p>

<p>Minutes passed, though they felt like hours, before we finally gave up. The crushing weight of reality settled in. My dad sat down in a nearby chair, his face pale, breathing heavily. His hand clutched at his chest as he gasped for air, shaking uncontrollably. He was having a panic attack. We rushed over, terrified that he might be having a heart attack. We were trying to calm him down, telling him to breathe. After a few minutes, his breathing steadied, and the colour slowly returned to his face.</p>

<p>We stared at her lifeless body for a while before discussing what to do next. 
We knew why she did it, or at least we thought we did. Her illness had taken over her life. Every day, she was in pain, suffering silently. Maybe she couldn’t bear it anymore, or perhaps she feared being a financial burden with the cost of her medication. We’ll never fully understand her reasons.</p>

<p>My mom, though, she hasn’t been the same since. Guilt consumes her. She wishes she had paid more attention to her mother’s suffering, taken her illness more seriously. She’s haunted by the things she didn’t do, the care she didn’t give. Watching her, heartbroken, unable to forgive herself, tears me apart. It’s like a wound that will never heal.</p>

<p>My grandmother is gone, and with her, the pain she endured. But the ones she left behind; we’re still here, carrying the weight of that day. The regrets, the what-ifs—they follow us. And though time may soften the grief, it never erases the memories.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What She Thinks She Owes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/what-she-think-she-owes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What She Thinks She Owes" /><published>2024-08-26T14:04:00+10:00</published><updated>2024-08-26T14:04:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/what-she-think-she-owes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/what-she-think-she-owes/"><![CDATA[<p>In the stillness of night, when voices fade and the world outside grows quiet, my mother carries her heaviest thoughts. She does not speak them; she keeps them locked inside, but I see the way her eyes dim when she thinks of her brothers.</p>

<p>She believes she is responsible for them. She believes their broken lives are somehow her fault. One of them, already fifty, has wasted his years chasing drugs. His health is gone, his blood sick, his body thin and fragile. He has no steady work, no money, and no reason to keep going except to ask others for help. And each time he reaches out, my mother answers, even though it cuts her deeper each time.</p>

<p>She does not have an income of her own. She is cared for, her needs are met, yet when her brother demands money, she cannot give from herself. She has to reach outward, asking from others so she can pass it on to him. It weighs on her dignity, though she rarely admits it. I know it hurts her, yet the guilt inside her whispers that she owes him, that she must not let him fall.</p>

<p>But I see the truth she cannot face. His life is not hers to fix. His ruin is not her burden. He chose his path; he chose the drugs; he chose to waste his strength. Now, when there is little left of him, he turns to her as if she were the reason for his collapse. And she believes it. She believes his failures are the shadow of her own mistakes.</p>

<p>It makes me angry, though I keep it hidden. Angry that she blames herself for what was never her doing. Angry that she bends under the weight of his demands while he takes without shame. Angry that her soft heart, which should be protected, is bruised again and again by someone who has given nothing back.</p>

<p>These are feelings I do not speak aloud. To tell her would only deepen her sorrow, and she already carries too much. So I hold my anger in silence, watching her give away what little she has, watching her carry the guilt of a man who never deserved her sacrifice.</p>

<p>What I wish she could see is simple. She has already given enough. She does not owe him her peace, her tears, or her dignity. His story is his own, and hers should not be chained to it. But I know she may never see it that way. She will go on carrying the guilt, because that is who she is. And I will go on loving her quietly, even as I ache with the anger she cannot bring herself to feel.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guilt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/guilt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guilt" /><published>2024-07-26T14:04:00+10:00</published><updated>2024-07-26T14:04:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/guilt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Whats-on-my-mind/guilt/"><![CDATA[<p>His life began with promise; a university student with dreams as wide as the sky above his small town. That sky once filled him with hope, but one night it became a dark cover hiding his ruin.</p>

<p>The evening had been alive with music and laughter. Friends gathered, drinks poured freely, and the energy of youth made him feel untouchable. The more he drank, the more he believed nothing could harm him. By the end of the night, unsteady on his feet, he convinced himself he could drive. The roads were quiet, and his home was close.
Inside the car, the world blurred. Streetlights smeared into streaks of colour, and the wheel felt heavy in his hands. On the seat beside him lay an empty bottle, rolling as the car swayed.</p>

<p>Then it happened. Ahead, a motorbike carried a small family—two parents and their child clinging to the middle. He saw them too late. The impact was sudden and sickening. The motorbike toppled, the parents thrown, the child struck hardest. The scene froze in his mind, a picture of horror carved into memory.</p>

<p>Instead of helping, fear drove him. His mind raced with what would happen if he stayed. Prison, shame, his future gone. In his country, with enough money, new names and new papers were possible. He chose escape. Within days, he had sold what he could, paid the right people, and disappeared. The boy was buried while he was boarding a plane.</p>

<p>Abroad, life became a shadow of itself. He changed his name and found work, but nothing felt real. The sun never seemed bright enough. Each drink reminded him of the bottle beside the passenger seat, each sound of children’s laughter twisted like a knife in his chest.
Crowded rooms made him feel more alone. He smiled when required, but the mask was brittle; every laugh from others grated against the silence inside him. At night, in his rented rooms, the darkness felt lighter than the weight pressing on his soul.</p>

<p>The child’s face followed him everywhere. On the bus, in the crowd, even in his dreams. He tried to live, but he was not living—only haunting himself. Strangers knew him by a false name, yet inside he was still the man who ran from the broken body of a child.</p>

<p>Years passed, but the guilt did not weaken; it grew. Every morning was punishment, every night a reminder. He was prisoner to a secret that rotted his spirit. In the end, there was no need for bars or judges. His guilt consumed him, leaving only a hollow man, fading quietly into nothing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tevy Tunsay</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test]]></summary></entry></feed>